OLIN KIRKLAND

Sternbergstraße 10 93047 Regensburg, Germany

plakat@live.com; +49 162 3720898

www.olinkirk.land

SUMMARY

I am an adaptable UI/UX developer with a passion for developing games, producing high quality OOP code, and creating user interfaces. My core experience includes front-end development and game design. My hobbies include reading fantasy novels and playing strategy, grand-strategy, or role-playing games.

SKILLS

- Programming: ActionScript, Flex, C#, JavaScript
- IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, FlashDevelop, Flash Builder
- Adobe Suite: Adobe Animate Professional, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop
- Communication: Fluent in English and German
- Worth Mentioning: Git, JSON, XML, RegEx

EDUCATION

George Mason University, Fairfax, VA, United States

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science September 2011 – June 2013

Oakton High School, Fairfax, VA, United States

Graduated with Advanced Placement September 2007 – June 2011

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DALLMEIER, Regensburg, BY, Germany

Flex Developer, May 2018 - Present

- Work closely with other programmers and designers to build intuitive user interfaces
- Develop various interactive modules for displaying and visualizing data
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Flex

HOUSTON MUSEUM OF NATURAL SCIENCE, Houston, TX, United States

Contract Interactive Developer, September 2017 – May 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen applications and kiosks for deployment in the Houston Museum of Natural Science, one of the most popular museums in the United States
- Worked closely with curators to build content rich exhibits that entertain and inform visitors
- Organized and led meetings with museum docents and volunteers
- Constructed and maintained a custom database for researchers building a dataset of European castles
- Designed and developed an interactive kiosk using LEAP Motion technology
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Adobe Flash, C#, LEAP Motion

PAUL BERNHARD EXHIBIT DESIGN AND CONSULTING, Houston, TX, United States

Lead Programmer, August 2015 – April 2018

- Developed interactive touch screen museum applications and information kiosks
- Directed the organization and implementation of museum content in custom applications
- Wrote programs to interface with and visualize data from custom hardware (sensors such industrial joysticks and Arduinos)

- Produced maps based on custom data sets using industry standard GIS tools
- Programmed visualizations for data from a wide variety of formats and sources including data from RESTful APIs related to energy sectors and extensive industry data sets
- Built APIs to interface with custom lighting controls
- Communicated with engineers, graphic designers, and researchers during development
- Created concepts and layouts as detailed storyboards for graphic designers to build on
- Managed the deployment of applications to their intended hardware
- Technologies: Adobe Air, Flex, C#, Unity, HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Flash, Arduino

ZENITH LEARNING, Houston, TX, United States

Teacher, January 2017 – June 2017

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to subjects including mechanical engineering and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

RENAISSANCE CHILD, Arlington, VA, United States

Technology Lead and Camp Instructor, April 2015 – September 2015

- Created lesson plans and activities relating to mechanical engineering, programming, and robotics
- Supervised, instructed, and assisted students in a classroom setting

ODESK.COM

Freelance Interactive Media Developer and Graphic Designer, June 2013 - April 2015

- Developed and implemented graphics and layouts for company applications
- Maintained an organized archive of versions and products
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Air, Adobe Flash

GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY HOUSING DEPARTMENT, Fairfax, VA, United States

Web and Flash Developer, January 2012 – May 2013

- Created concepts and sample layouts to run by management
- Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, Adobe Flash

PERSONAL PROJECTS

REALMS

Procedural World and Map Simulation, 2019

MAZE

Procedural Maze Solving Game, 2017

ALTAR (GLOBAL GAME JAM 2016)

Multiplayer Platformer, 2016

ENTROPY

Physics-based Arcade Game, 2015

SWEET DREAMS (GLOBAL GAME JAM 2014)

Platformer, 2014

AMBER WORLD

Turn Based Role-Playing Game, 2013